[{"name": "Apprentice", "description": "I will follow where you lead. You have spent your life studying under a mentor. This mentor was likely a master of your chosen class. Perhaps your mentor found you when you were at your lowest point, and helped to raise you up. Or perhaps you were pressed into your mentor's service against your will. Whether your relationship with your mentor was postive or negative, they have taught you enough to make it on your own. Your time as an apprentice has marked you, leaving an impact that will last a lifetime.", "options": [{"question": "How did you meet your mentor?", "answers": ["I was forced into my mentor's service.", "My mentor saw potential in me and asked me to follow them.", "My mentor rescued me and took me in.", "My mentor has raised me since I was very little.", "My mentor is a respected peer.", "I have no memory of meeting my mentor."]}, {"question": "How is your relationship with your mentor?", "answers": ["I have a deep respect for my mentor. I am a diligent student and follow their orders to the letter.", "My mentor moves too slowly. I feel like they are holding back.", "I am one of many of my mentor's students, but I am their favorite.", "I am one of many of my mentor's students, and feel the need to prove myself.", "My mentor is amazing, and I would follow them to the ends of the earth. Some people would call my devotion to them unhealthy.", "I am a disappointment to my mentor."]}, {"question": "Where is your mentor now?", "answers": ["My mentor was killed right in front of me.", "My mentor disappeared mysteriously, leaving only a few clues as to their whereabouts.", "My mentor didn't go anywhere! They are still traveling with me.", "I ran away from my mentor or was kicked out.", "My mentor decided that it was time for me to get experience in the world by myself.", "My mentor sent me on a mission while they attended to other matters."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Three gold per character level", "An Adventurer's Kit", "Apprentice's Tools", "Commoner's Clothing"]}, {"name": "Amnesiac", "description": "Bleary eyed, you awaken. Who are you? Where are you? As an amnesiac, your memories have been stolen from you. Even the most powerful magic cannot take everything, however, and you are left with a single memory, a few items from your past, and one other thing that you are sure wasn't with you to begin with. As you adventure, you will meet people from your forgotten past, and begin to reconstruct your memories.", "options": [{"question": "Where did you wake up?", "answers": ["I woke up alone in the wilderness, far from civilization.", "I washed up on the coast.", "In the gutters of a city.", "On a healer's bed.", "In the company of a person I swear I've never met.", "In a prison.", "In a grave.", "On a ship or in a cart."]}, {"question": "What is the one thing you can you remember?", "answers": ["A person I love.", "A person I hate.", "A place.", "An object.", "A sense of purpose.", "A feeling of dread."]}, {"question": "What two things did you wake up with (roll twice)?", "answers": ["A magic item that I don't recognize.", "A strange marking or tatoo.", "An unfamiliar magic weapon which fits my hand perfectly.", "An invitation.", "A piece of information written on me.", "A pouch full of gold (50 per character level).", "Fine clothes.", "A voice in my head."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Two gold per character level", "A Potion of Minor Healing", "Custom Clothes"]}, {"name": "Chosen", "description": "Destiny awaits. As a chosen, you must rise to meet it. Maybe a prophecy spoke of your birth, or perhaps you accidentally touched the wrong relic. Most chosen don't know exactly what they were selected to do; prophecies are vague, and deities and panels of aged wizards don't share details. As you adventure, you will uncover more about the path ahead, and will have to decide whether or not you want to follow it.", "options": [{"question": "How were you chosen?", "answers": ["I was chosen by a prophecy", "I was chosen by a higher power.", "I was born or created specifically for my destiny.", "I accidentally stumbled into my destiny by doing something I wasn't supposed to.", "I was one of multiple candidates for my destiny, and was chosen via a trial.", "I volunteered for my destiny."]}, {"question": "What is your relationship with your destiny?", "answers": ["I am trying to live up to it.", "I am trying to escape it.", "It's a long way off, so I try not to think about it.", "I am skeptical of it. I don't believe that I have a destiny.", "I take it for granted. It is just part of me.", "It is all that I care about. I am rushing towards it with single minded drive.", "It makes me confident that I can take on anything. Bring it on!", "It is a burden that I must carry alone."]}, {"question": "What two things need to happen before your destiny can unfold (roll twice)?", "answers": ["I must master an ancient technique.", "I must find or reforge a powerful artifact.", "I must traverse the ways to enter another realm.", "I must defeat a powerful foe.", "I must visit mystical sites.", "I must visit a wise master."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Five gold per character level", "A Masterwork 1 Shortsword or Rapier", "A Potion of Minor Healing", "An Adventurer's Kit", "Commoner's Clothing"]}, {"name": "Entertainer", "description": "To perform is to live, and as an entertainer, you are alive. Perhaps you travel from town to town, regailing locals with stories for ale and coin. Or maybe you are a court bard, singing ballads to lords and ladies in grand halls. Whatever your path, your ability to enthral and entertain will serve you on your journey.", "options": [{"question": "Where do you typically perform?", "answers": ["At court, surrounded by lords and ladies.", "In seedy barrooms.", "I am a one person show. I roll into town and set up.", "In a theater.", "I am always performing.", "In a travelling company."]}, {"question": "Why did you become an adventurer?", "answers": ["I began adventuring to find inspiration for my performances.", "While digging through old lore for my performances, I discovered something that seemed worth investigating.", "I became enraptured by my own stories.", "I hate to be out of the know. Hearing tales of adventure, I simply had to join.", "I recently recieved an invitation from an old acquaintence, which looks like it will be more than I bargained for.", "Something terrible happened to those I care about. I took up the mantel of adventurer so that I can grow stronger."]}, {"question": "What is your entertainer's quirk?", "answers": ["I am prideful. An insult to my art is an insult to me.", "I try not to get attached to any person or place because I'm always leaving.", "I will never turn down a good time.", "I am full of childlike joy, and have trouble being serious.", "I burst into performance at random.", "I do everything with a flair of showmanship."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Five gold per character level", "A Common Dagger", "An Adventurer's Kit", "A Performer's Kit", "A Pack Animal", "Entertainer's Clothes"]}, {"name": "Explorer", "description": "The unknown calls you. As an explorer, you will heed the summons? Some explorers spend years pouring over dusty tomes before setting off into the wild beyond. Others begin moving towards the unknown with their first steps. It takes a special type of person to plunge into danger and find things of which others have hardly dreampt. This passion usually has a focus; for some explorers, it is finding lost civilizations. For others, it is studying the biology of unknown monsters. Whatever your passion, it is sure to lead you on dangerous and epic adventures.", "options": [{"question": "What is your passion?", "answers": ["I want to discover new places, flora, and fauna!", "I want to uncover lost civilizations!", "I am drawn by the promise of treasure!", "I want to discover more about the magic that fills the world!", "I want to study monsters!", "I want to study dieties and demons!"]}, {"question": "Where did you find your passion?", "answers": ["When I was very young, I used to have dreams about my passion, including some things that I shouldn't have known about.", "My mother or father kept a locked room full of notes and artifacts. I was always trying to sneak in.", "I went to an academy and my horizons were wildly expanded.", "I had a mentor who was an explorer. They taught me everything I know.", "I was locked inside as a child. All that I had were books about my passion and dreams of the world outside.", "I have suffered incredible hardships. Pursuing my passion is the only way to make it all feel worth it."]}, {"question": "What is your explorer's quirk?", "answers": ["I overplan everything. My bags are always packed to bursting.", "I fly by the seat of my pants. Onward!", "I think that everything is a clue.", "I am incredibly interested in objects others find mundane. I love taking samples.", "I am so used to roughing it in the wilds that I no longer fit in society.", "I have an anecdote for every situation. \"This reminds me of that time in the goblin city of Gnorth, when...\"", "I am always naming the new things that I find, even if they may have already been discovered.", "All of my equipment has been with me for so long that I consider it \"trusty,\" and refuse to upgrade."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Five gold per character level", "A common Dagger", "An Adventurer's Kit", "A map of the region", "A spyglass", "Commoner's Clothing"]}, {"name": "Wisdom", "description": "You will be their guide. As a wisdom, you may have been a medicine person in a village or an advisor to a lord or lady. People are drawn to you for advice, as if by some unseen force. Wisdoms are idiosyncratic by nature. Some speak in cryptic riddles while others seem to peer into your soul. All wisdoms draw their advice from somewhere, be it from booksmarts, rituals, or the ancient teachings of elders past. A wisdom is a welcome member of any party, helping to steer adventurers in the right direction.", "options": [{"question": "For how long have you been a wisdom?", "answers": ["I am new to this. I've barely started.", "I have been a wisdom for some time and have begun to get the hang of it.", "I have been a wisdom for decades, and have faced many hard decisions.", "I am ancient. I've been a wisdom since time immemorable."]}, {"question": "What is your Wisdom Quirk?", "answers": ["I am mysterious. I speak in riddles.", "I am incomprehensible. I make jokes that only I understand as I steer people in the right direction.", "I am a straight shooter. I tell it exactly like it is.", "I act older than I am, and expect others to help me with tasks. I might even have a walking stick.", "I am cool and collected. When I speak, I expect others to listen.", "I am deeply unsure of myself. I am not worthy of the respect people give me."]}, {"question": "From what source do you draw your wisdom?", "answers": ["I am learned. My wisdom comes from booksmarts.", "I am knowledgeableI have my fingers in everything, and gather information from everywhere.", "I am worldwise. My wisdom comes from experience.", "I am a conduit. I receive my wisdom from visions, signs, and rituals.", "I am a member of a tradition. I was trained in the old ways.", "I am a charlatan. I am just faking it."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Two gold per character level", "A Common Quarterstaff", "Two Potions of Minor Healing", "A Potion of Greater Healing", "A set of Robes"]}, {"name": "Inventor", "description": "Your ideas will shape the world. As an inventor, you while away your hours bringing wonderous things to life. An inventor's mind spins as it fills with the promise of things not yet built. As an adventurer, you likely won't have a sterile laboratory to work in, and inventions made in the field often go haywire. Necessity is the mother of invention, and many of your best designs will be built in the wilds. These contraptions will help get you out of many binds, even if they put you in just as many precarious situations.", "options": [{"question": "How did you come across your knack for invention?", "answers": ["I was born with an inventor's mind. I think analytically and am always looking to optimize.", "When I was younger, I saw a contraption that enthralled me. I had to try to build one for myself. The rest is history.", "I was apprenticed to an inventor, who taught me everything they know. The quirks of their method are still evident in my work.", "Necessity is the mother of invention. I build things expressly because I need to in order to be successful.", "Sometimes, I swear that I hear a voice, guiding me in my work. I call it my muse, but I can't help but wonder if it's real.", "Life is too difficult, and I am always trying to make it easier. Some people call me lazy, but I think my time is better spent inventing than doing things the regular way."]}, {"question": "What is your inventor's quirk?", "answers": ["I have an invention for everything, and can't function without them.", "I am always asking my friends to test my prototypes.", "I am cool and calculating, always analytical.", "I am absorbed by my work, often muttering to myself and scratching designs in my notebooks.", "I like to test my designs on unsuspecting people.", "I am always trying to help out, even if it doesn't always work."]}, {"question": "What tends to go wrong with your inventions?", "answers": ["They tend to work a little too well.", "They are always slightly more dangerous than I mean for them to be.", "They usually accomplish something different than my original goal.", "I overengineer my inventions to solve simple problems.", "They all have my own unique sense of flair, which other people fail to appreciate.", "They have a mind of their own."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Five gold per character level", "A Common Handgun", "Tinker's Tools", "Commoner's Clothes"]}, {"name": "Blackmailed", "description": "To resist is death. As a Blackmailed, someone is controlling you. Maybe it is a wicked lord, threatening to kill your family if you don't comply, or perhaps it is an evil mage that has you in their thrall. No matter what, they are holding something over you, and the cost of standing up to them is too great. As you adventure, they may try to force you to take the wrong path until you finally find the ability to stand up to them.", "options": [{"question": "What did you do before you were a hunted?", "answers": ["Roll 1d20, select a second background, and answer any relevant questions. To merge the two backgrounds successfully, you may need to skip some questions. You begin with any starting equipment from your second background."]}, {"question": "Who holds sway over you?", "answers": ["A corrupt official.", "A bitter rival.", "A demon or diety that you do not align with.", "A cunning monster.", "A shadow organization.", "I don't know who they are, but I have suspicions."]}, {"question": "How do they control you?", "answers": ["They have my family.", "They have bound me with magic.", "They have something that I need badly.", "I owe them an enormous debt.", "They have control of my livlihood.", "They know information that must be kept secret."]}], "starting_equipment": ["A cryptic letter from your blackmailer"]}, {"name": "Highborn", "description": "Wealth and glory. You are a member of the upper crust of society. Perhaps you were born with a silver spoon in your mouth, or maybe you clawed your way to the top. Your affluence brings with it privelege, and your money has colored your personality. It takes a real push for a highborn to leave their home and take up the life of an adventurer. Some must prove themselves, while others are fleeing coups or wicked family members. Highborn rarely travel alone -- usually, they have a servant in their retinue. A highborn in the adventuring party can be both a blessing and a curse. Their funds and connections often help a party get their foot in the door, but highborn personalitites often leave something to be desired.", "options": [{"question": "Why did you leave the comfort of your home?", "answers": ["My family was deposed. I am on the run.", "My family is in danger, I hope to find a way to save them.", "I am on a journey to prove myself.", "I ran away from home.", "I am travelling abroad for pleasure.", "Life as a noble was never for me. I burned my bridges and left."]}, {"question": "What is your highborn's quirk?", "answers": ["I believe that I deserve respect and veneration from everyone.", "I do not understand the value of money.", "I'm so used to having things done for me that I sometimes forget to do them for myself.", "I am very easily overwhelmed by minor inconveniences.", "I am fascinated by the way that ordinary people do things, and never learned many life skills.", "I refuse to take help from anyone."]}, {"question": "What is your servant like?", "answers": ["They are an old curmudgeon who only wants what's best for me. They're always trying to keep me out of trouble.", "They are young and naive and excited to experience the world. They're always getting into trouble.", "They are shy, rarely talking and usually hiding behind me.", "They are prim and proper and constantly complain about conditions while adventuring.", "They are my personal chef. They have a sweet disposition and are always trying to fatten me up.", "They are aged. They have a lot of wisdom, but not as much pep in their step as they used to have."]}], "starting_equipment": ["100 gold per character level", "A Masterwork 1 Weapon", "An Adventurer's Kit", "A Potion of Major Healing", "Three sets of fine clothes", "A set of armor", "A signant of your family's house"]}, {"name": "Disciple", "description": "I put my faith in you. As a disciple, you are a member of a religious order. Some diciples are born into their faith, while others find it when they are older or are pressed into service. No matter what, you are devout, and your faith has shaped your personality and how you present to the world. As you set out as an adventurer, you may trust that your faith will not lead you astray.", "options": [{"question": "How did you find you faith?", "answers": ["When I was at my lowest point, my faith found me.", "When someone was dying, I struck a deal.", "I was inducted into my religion when I was very young, and have never known anything else.", "I was forced into a life of faith.", "A wise mentor helped guide me on my path to faith.", "My faith started as a way to help me keep a low profile."]}, {"question": "What is your disciple's quirk?", "answers": ["I let faith be my guide. I pray whenever I am in a difficult situation, and trust that everything will turn out alright.", "I always put others before myself.", "I have a deep love for my fellow people. I am a servant to all.", "I believe that it is my duty to convert as many people as possible to my faith.", "I am deeply angered by wickedness. I will stand up against any injustice.", "I follow the letter of my teachings, but never questioned what they actually mean."]}, {"question": "What is your relationship with your faith?", "answers": ["I try to run, but my faith follows me.", "I try my best to follow my faith's teachings, but I don't always get it right.", "My faith is unshakable. I am a paragon of my faith and an example to other followers.", "I feel deeply unworthy of the blessings I am given.", "The fire of my faith is strong. I try to convert anyone I can.", "I have fallen out of favor with my faith."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Three gold per character level", "A holy symbol", "A Ritual Kit", "A Common Dagger which deals 1d4 bonus radiant damage", "A set of robes"]}, {"name": "Recluse", "description": "You are your own best friend. As a recluse, you have shut yourself away from society, wrapping yourself in total solitude. Maybe you have locked yourself in a high tower, filled with books that speak of adventure you are sure you will never know, or perhaps you have taken to the wilderness, keeping your own council among the animals and trees. But something has made you break your solitude, and you are now plunged into a world of sound and movement and other people. All recluses pick up ticks during their long hours spent alone, and you are no exception. As you adventure, you must strive to overcome your introversion and to become the hero you are destined to be.", "options": [{"question": "Where did you hide yourself away?", "answers": ["In my home in the city, with the door sealed tight.", "On a self-sustaining plot of land which I cultivated.", "In the wilderness, hunting and fishing for my meals.", "In a temple, shrine, or monestary, locked in silent contemplation.", "On a boat, cart, or other vehichle.", "In my workshop, tinkering on my projects."]}, {"question": "What has caused you to break your solitude?", "answers": ["One of my few friends is in need of help.", "I am forcing myself to expand my horizons.", "I was driven from my safehaven by enemies.", "I came into posession of vital information which I must deliver.", "After years of working on a project, I suddenly realized that I was finished.", "I left my safehaven because I am in need of help."]}, {"question": "What is your Recluse's Quirk?", "answers": ["I talk to myself about everything.", "I am afraid of wide open spaces.", "I am constantly discheveled and my table manners are terrible.", "I am very distrusting of other people.", "I am socially awkward and bad at reading people.", "I don't value the contributions of others. My opinion is the only one that matters."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Two gold per character level", "An Adventurer's Kit", "A memento", "Custom clothing"]}, {"name": "Retired Adventurer", "description": "You were a legend. As a retired adventurer, you may believed that your best days were behind you. As a youth, you went on grand quests with an adventuring party, and accomplished heroic deeds. For some reason, you laid down your arms. Maybe your quest was finished successfully, or maybe it ended in bitter defeat. Regardless, something has thrust you back into the wold of adventure. But you are older than you once were, and you will need a new party at your back as you set out on the road to adventure.", "options": [{"question": "Why did you retire?", "answers": ["I was injured.", "I met someone and settled down.", "I completed my quest and returned home a legend.", "I had a falling out with my adventuring party", "Almost everyone in my adventuring party died.", "I failed my quest and returned home a disgrace."]}, {"question": "What has pulled you back out of retirement?", "answers": ["I heard tales of ill dealings, and knew that I had to help.", "I recieved a note from an old friend, begging me to come to them.", "I recieved word of an old enemy that I thought was long dead.", "The new life that I had built for myself fell apart. I have nothing left but adventuring.", "I was done with adventure, but it wasn't done with me. Someone I love was taken from me or killed, and I must avenge them or get them back.", "I was bored. I have longed for the thrill of adventure for years, and I am finally heeding the call."]}, {"question": "What is your Retired Adventurer's Quirk?", "answers": ["I am always telling unbelievable stories about the old days. If you've got a story, I can top it.", "I often complain about how things have changed. Everything has gotten so expensive!", "I'm not as quick on my feet as I used to be.", "I'm getting old. I need a good bed and real food, as often as I can get them.", "I forget things.", "I tell it like it is. I'll give you advice even if you don't want it.", "I try to be a parental figure to my adventuring party.", "I am hiding secret pain. When I feel desparate, I will do anything to make it go away."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Five gold per character level", "A Masterwork 1 Weapon", "An Adventurer's Kit", "A Potion of Minor Healing", "Custom Clothing"]}, {"name": "Ruffian", "description": "Laws are made to be broken. As a ruffian, you were a criminal, living on the wrong side of the law. Maybe you were a thief or smuggler. Maybe you took the law into your own hands. No matter what, what you have done has weighed on you, and you are trying to turn over a new leaf. It can be hard to stay on the straight and narrow, but as an adventurer, you must walk the path of a hero. With your party at your side, you will take your experiences and use them to fight the villains that stalk the realms so that you can atone for the crimes of your past.", "options": [{"question": "What sort of crimes did you commit?", "answers": ["I was a sneakthief. I picked pockets and broke into homes.", "I was a highwayman. I stopped travellers on the road and robbed them.", "I was a con-artist. I duped people out of their money.", "I was a smuggler. I sold illegal goods on the blackmarket.", "I was a high-class criminal. I was in a position of power, and used it to line my own pockets.", "I took the law into my own hands."]}, {"question": "Why did you leave your life of crime?", "answers": ["I was caught and served a punishment.", "I had one too many close calls.", "I had a falling out with my associates.", "I was only a criminal because I had to be. I got out as soon as I could.", "No matter how hard I try to give up being a criminal, I keep getting pulled right back in.", "I found something that made my future brighter. I wouldn't risk it for anything."]}, {"question": "What is your ruffian's quirk?", "answers": ["I always believe that I am in the right. The ends justify the means.", "I am deeply aware of my demons and will try my hardest to avoid breaking the law again.", "I have a mark that brands me as a criminal. Other people distrust me because of it, no matter how hard I try to atone.", "I am deeply tempted by my vices, and often slip back into my old ways. However, I would never harm my friends or my adventuring party.", "I have delusions of granduer. I am the greatest criminal the world has ever seen!", "I have deep code of honor which dictates how I act. I will only harm someone if my code calls for it."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Five gold per character level", "A Thieve's Kit", "Commoner's Clothes", "A dark cloak"]}, {"name": "Layperson", "description": "You are the salt of the earth. As a layperson, you have lived a largely uneventful life. There many varieties of laypeople; you may have been a successful businessperson, or maybe you aimlessly drank away your meager earnings. Regardless, something has happened, and now you find yourself thrust into a world of adventure that you never planned for. The average layperson hasn't experienced much of the world. Some are distrustful of new experiences, while others want to see and do everything. No matter your inclination, you will rise above your humble origins and grow to become a mighty adventurer.", "options": [{"question": "What was your life like before you were an adventurer?", "answers": ["I was successful. I owned a shop and made good money.", "I was aimless. I toiled away as a day laborer and spent my earnings at taverns.", "I was a hard worker. I farmed the land and grew crops to sell and to see me through the winter.", "I was a layabout. My friends and family supported me.", "I was happy. My path was clear, and I thought I knew what the future held.", "I was bored. I went through the motions and excelled, but my heart wasn't in my work."]}, {"question": "What is your Layperson's Quirk?", "answers": ["I want to try everything! I am constantly blown away by new experiences.", "When I am nervous or in an awkward situation, I make smalltalk and undoubtably bring up the weather.", "I am deeply superstitious. I carry a number of deeprooted traditions with me.", "I think the rich live worry free and are the cause of all of my woes.", "I am frightened of monsters. It takes bravery for me to stand up and fight.", "I only trust things that are familiar to me. I won't eat foreign foods, and fear the worst when meeting new people."]}, {"question": "Why did you take up a life of adventure?", "answers": ["Everything that I cared about was threatened.", "Everything that I cared about was destroyed.", "I was given an offer that I couldn't refuse.", "I was selected by another adventurer to go on a journey.", "I was in the wrong place at the wrong time, and experienced something that I shouldn't have.", "A magic item appeared out of nowhere and thrust me into a world of adventure."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Three gold per character level", "A Common Quarterstaff", "A Pack Animal", "Commoner's Clothes"]}, {"name": "Scholar", "description": "The pen is mightier than the sword! Though I do carry a dagger, just in case... As a scholar, you are among the learned people in the realms. Usually found at academies of higher learning, scholars almost always specialize in a specific field of inquiry. Some study the wonders of magic, while others are rooted in more practical matters, such as the politics of the land. Many scholars are shut-in by nature, and going into the field is a feat of necessity and bravery. Whatever your reason for setting out on an adventure, your knowledge is sure to be of help! Even if you did spend your youth studying the intricacies of the fairy court...", "options": [{"question": "What is your area of research?", "answers": ["Magic! I explore the wonders of the arcane.", "History! I marvel at the glory of the ancients!", "Monsters! From dragons to tadlings, I want to know everything!", "Politics! The who's who of the court gives my life purpose!", "Something obscure! You've probably never heard of it...", "Geography! I want to map out places unknown!"]}, {"question": "What is your scholar's quirk?", "answers": ["I am scatterbrained. My thoughts flit from thing to thing and I sometimes trail off while speak...", "I am pompous about the area of my research. I'm an expert, you know!", "I am constantly baffled when my booksmarts don't apply to real life.", "I cart around far more than I need. I am basically a walking library.", "I have imposter syndrome. I don't think I'm as intelligent as I actually am.", "I am always taking notes, studying, and asking questions, even if it is socially unacceptable."]}, {"question": "What forced you into the field?", "answers": ["I discovered something of great import, and I must investigate it!", "I want to achieve tenure at my institution, and to do that, I need field experience.", "Going on adventures has been my life's dream!", "My presence was requested by a collegue to whom I owe a favor.", "I was thrown out of academia in disgrace.", "I suspect that my rival is close to a major discovery, and I must beat them to the chase!"]}], "starting_equipment": ["Three gold per character level", "A collection of books", "Fine Clothes", "Commoner's Clothes", "A map of a distant location"]}, {"name": "Hunted", "description": "It follows. Something from your past is chasing you, and it's getting closer. Maybe you are being hunted by monsters after stumbling into a dark ritual, or perhaps an ex-lover has sent assassins to kill you in the night. No matter what, you must keep your eyes open, lest your past catch up with you when you least expect it.", "options": [{"question": "What did you do before you were a hunted?", "answers": ["Roll 1d20, select a second background, and answer any relevant questions. To merge the two backgrounds successfully, you may need to skip some questions. You begin with any starting equipment from your second background."]}, {"question": "Who is hunting you?", "answers": ["I am being hunted by Monsters.", "I am being hunted by bounty hunters.", "I am being hunted by my old associates.", "I am being hunted by members of an order.", "I am being hunted by a crime-lord's hired assassins.", "I don't know who is hunting me."]}, {"question": "Why are you being hunted?", "answers": ["I don't know. I've always lived an ordinary life and kept out of trouble.", "I saw something that I shouldn't have. That's what I get for sticking my nose into things.", "I stole something valuable to them.", "I ruined their plans, and now they're after me.", "I am valuable to them.", "I was in a romantic relationship and it ended very badly."]}], "starting_equipment": ["An item related to the person, group, or creature that is hunting you"]}, {"name": "Servant", "description": "I obey. As a servant, you are bound to attend to a master. Some servants are paid a wage for their services, others are bound by law, or honor, or magic. A servant's feelings towards their superiors can be complicated. Some servants are filled with hatred, others are blindly loyal. As you set out on your journey, your life of service will undoubtably color your adventures.", "options": [{"question": "Who do you serve?", "answers": ["A noble house.", "A scholar or mage.", "An affluent businessperson", "A family to whom I owe a blood debt."]}, {"question": "What are your feelings towards the people you serve?", "answers": ["I owe them everything. I will be loyal until the day I die.", "They are terrible people. I want to be free of them.", "I used them for connections and opportunities, nothing more.", "I am in love with one of my masters.", "I was born into servitude, and taught to obey.", "I am bound by honor -- my feelings do not matter.", "I am bound by magic to serve. I cannot disobey.", "I have a good and simple life, for which I am grateful."]}, {"question": "Where are the people you serve now?", "answers": ["They were destroyed.", "They had darker dealings than I imagined.", "They sent me on a mission.", "I am accompanying one of them on a journey.", "I am supposed to meet one of them.", "I have run away from them."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Three gold per character level", "A letter of invitation from the people you serve", "Servant's Garb"]}, {"name": "Brawler", "description": "Tough as nails. Skilled combatants, fighters often serve as townsguards, sellswords, or thugs. No matter which side of the law they are on, all fighters have a reason that they charge headlong into conflict, noble or otherwise. Many adventurers start out as fighters, though it can be a rude awakening when they learn that not all problems can be solved with a swift blow to the head.", "options": [{"question": "Why do you fight?", "answers": ["I'm good at it. I've been fighting since I was born.", "For glory. I want songs to be sung about me.", "For money. Fighting is my trade, and it pays the bills -- barely.", "For honor. I always stand up for what I believe in.", "For the love of it. Nothing wakes you up like a bust in the jaw.", "For duty. I fight to protect those I care about."]}, {"question": "Where do you tend to fight?", "answers": ["I am a competition fighter.", "I have been known to get into a tavern brawl or two.", "I served my country.", "I am a sellsword.", "I am usually on the wrong side of the law.", "I am a guard."]}, {"question": "What is your fighter's quirk?", "answers": ["I am aware that I am capable of great violence. I work hard to keep that in check.", "Violence is usually the answer to my problems.", "I've been punched in the head a few too many times. Sometimes it takes me a moment before I understand things.", "I am brusque, and very confident.", "People find me intimidating, but I am very loyal to my friends.", "I have a happy go lucky attitude, but I can flip at a moment's notice."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Five gold per character level", "Two Common Weapons", "An Adventurer's Kit", "Commoner's Clothes", "A Potion of Greater Healing"]}, {"name": "Wanderer", "description": "Wandering, but not lost. Wanderers roam the realms, coming and going as they please. Some wanderers are travelling salesman, others sail on great ships, or work as migrant laborers. No matter where you came from, something has lead you to join an adventuring party, and to seek to help other people. As a wanderer, you are used to the harsh conditions of the wilds, and have far-flung connections that may help your adventuring party.", "options": [{"question": "What lead to your wandering?", "answers": ["I have the itch. Discovering new things and exploring new places is what keeps me going.", "I am searching for something, but I've never found it. I have nowhere I belong.", "There are those who would do me harm if they found me, so I never stay in one place for long.", "I like to keep my finger on the pulse of the world. I travel, observe, and spread information.", "I am no longer welcome back home.", "I am a member of an order of wanderers."]}, {"question": "What lead you to become an adventurer?", "answers": ["It was an accident, I assure you. I was sucked into this whole mess when it affected me directly.", "I bore witness to a great misfortune. Ever since, I do everything I can to help people.", "I am in need of gold. Money is hard to come by, and adventuring pays well.", "It started as a favor. Someone was in need and I helped.", "I have a strict code of honor. I cannot turn a blind eye.", "I have done terrible things. I am trying to atone for them by adventuring."]}, {"question": "What is your wanderers quirk?", "answers": ["I am very frugal, and have very few possessions.", "At this point, I actually prefer sleeping in stables or outside of town.", "I try to bring a smile to every face I can. Usually, it earns me supper.", "I know someone in every town. I am always dropping in on old friends and bringing news of the land.", "I sometimes talk aloud to myself or my animals. Because of all of the time I've spent alone, I am always saying too much or too little.", "People tend to distrust me. I have to work to get them to let me in."]}], "starting_equipment": ["Three gold per character level", "A Common Dagger", "A Common Short Bow", "A Pack Animal", "An Adventuring Kit", "Commoner's Clothing"]}, {"name": "Urchin", "description": "Born on the streets. As an urchin, you have fought to scrape by on the fringes of society. Many urchins beg for their food, or are thrown into orphanages. Others turn to crime and become pickpockets or thugs. All of this is in service of surival, of finding food for just one more day. No matter what, something has changed for you, and you are pulling yourself up, and out of the streets. You have been called to become an adventurer, and just maybe you can save those you care about and put your past behind you.", "options": [{"question": "What is your Urchin's Quirk?", "answers": ["I eat ravenously whenever there is food available, sometimes until I am sick.", "I have to resist the urge to pickpocket, even to this day.", "I have a deep distrust of law enforcement.", "I have a sickly constitution and a cough that will never go away.", "I have a good sense of when danger is coming, and my instinct is to run and not look back.", "I keep my possessions close. I get very angry when people touch my things."]}, {"question": "How did you make it on the streets?", "answers": ["I had a sibling who looked out for me.", "I had a sibling who I had to look out for.", "I joined a gang of thugs and became a criminal.", "I was in and out of an orphanage as a kid.", "I was resilient, found work, and pulled myself up by my bootstraps.", "I barely scraped by. I begged for what I got. Sometimes, I took without asking."]}, {"question": "How did you end up as an adventurer?", "answers": ["It's a way to earn money.", "I always idolized adventurers and wanted to be one.", "I was pulled out of my situation by an adventurer and never looked back.", "I got tied up in dark dealings. I know that I need a change before it's too late.", "I have people who look up to me. I can't let them down.", "I let down the people I care about. I have to atone for what I've done."]}], "starting_equipment": ["One gold piece per character level", "A Common Dagger", "Commoner's Clothes", "A Memento"]}]